Finding Aid for Fred DeWitt papers, 1939-1979
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Fred DeWitt papers 1939-1979
DeWitt, Fred.
0.3 linear feet
89163 Aa 2
Secretary of the engineering class of 1929 of the University of Michigan. Files relating to class reunions, including group photographs; also various subject files.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was donated by Fred DeWitt, (Donor no. 7481 ), member of the 1929 engineering class at the University of Michigan.
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Fred DeWitt was secretary of the engineering class of 1929 of the University of Michigan.
The DeWitt papers are in effect the records of the class of 1929 and are primarily concerned with class reunions. The first reunion was the 10th, held in 1939, followed by the 20th in 1949. Thereafter reunions were held every five years through the 50th reunion. The 1929 Engineers were a well organized group. They printed and distributed class directories in conjunction with their reunions and kept in close contact throughout the years. The collection includes letters, announcements and reports on activities for each of the reunions. Of note is a questionnaire filled out during the 20th reunion which asked about the present activities of the graduates, their occupations and families. Also included is a brief section on changes made to the school of engineering prior to the proposed Michigan engineering centennial in 1954. Other information consists of photographs taken at the various reunions and log books of dues and guest registers.
Subjects:
University of Michigan--Alumni and alumnae.; University of Michigan. College of Engineering. Class of 1929.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Camp Davis (University of Michigan); University of Michigan--Alumni and alumnae.; University of Michigan. College of Engineering. Class of 1929.; University of Michigan--Students--1921-1930.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.
- Reunion files
  - 10th Reunion, June 16-17, 1939
    - General material (Box 1)
    - Guest register (Box 1)
    - Group photograph (Box 1)
  - 20th Reunion, June 10, 1949
    - General material (Box 1)
    - Questionnaire (Box 1)
    - Photograph album (Box 1)
  - 25th Reunion, June 10-12, 1954
    - General material (Box 1)
    - Group photograph (Box 1)
    - Photograph album (Box 1)
  - 30th Reunion, June 11-12, 1959
    - General material (Box 1)
    - Group photograph (Box 1)
    - Photograph album (Box 1)
    - Snapshots (Box 1)
  - 35th Reunion, May 21-23, 1964
    - General material (Box 1)
    - Group photograph (Box 1)
  - 40th Reunion, October 10-11, 1969
    - General material (Box 1)
    - Complaints following reunion and proposed class letter (Box 1)
    - Group photograph (Box 1)
    - Snapshots (Box 1)
  - 42nd Reunion, October 15-16, 1971
    - General material (Box 1)
  - 45th Reunion, October 25-26, 1974
    - General material (Box 1)
  - 50th Reunion, April 26-28, 1979
    - General material (Box 1)
    - Group photograph (Box 1)
- Class miscellaneous
  - Notes on changes made to Engineering School and statement about Phoenix Project for centennial celebration of Engineering School in 1954 material 1950-1952 (Box 1)
  - Financial reports of class of 1929 engineering loan fund, 1959-1982 (Box 1)
  - Dues payment record, 1939-1974 (Box 1)
  - Guest register, 1949-1979 (Box 1)
  - Photographs from engineering camps in Jackson Hole, Wyoming and Camp Davis in Michigan (Box 1)